Gillian A Roberts

- **Q** 07825959795
- ★ gillianaroberts.com
- Glasgow

SUMMARY

Career Changer -

I recently made a career shift into software development. With over 20 years in the residential property industry, I've developed strong skills in sales, product development, customer service, and project management where I've found that my experience in property sales and design share many valuable traits. Overall my attention to detail and ability to thrive under pressure, meeting tight deadlines have proven to be assets in this new venture.

Additionally, I'm mindful of various essential technologies, adapting to new tools, and continuously learning. In the property industry, staying updated with market trends was vital, and I've carried this adaptability into the tech world.

I've always been a knowledge sharer and am keen on collaboration, attributes that have served me well in my CodeClan journey. This transition has allowed me to explore both front-end and back-end web development, while embracing practices such as Agile, Scrum, Test-Driven Development, RESTful API design, and efficient GitHub usage. Real-world projects marked the end of my journey, opening doors to a rewarding career in software development and turning my lifelong dream into reality.

PROJECTS

Group Project 1 of 4 Contributors (duration 2 weeks)

Wiggle Waggy Walks - React, Java, Firebase 7

11/2023 - 11/2023

10/2023 - 10/2023

- Proficient use of Java and Spring, contributing to the development of core app components
- Utilised Agile methodologies for efficient project management
- Implemented authentication, real-time chat and image upload features using Firebase to enhance user engagement
- · Conducted thorough testing, including unit, integration, and user acceptance testing, to ensure app reliability
- · Demonstrated the ability to meet strict project deadlines and perform well under pressure

Group Project - 1 of 4 Contributors (duration 1 week)

Sizzle & Grill Aromatic Recipes - React, MongoDB 7

- Embraced Agile and Scrum methodologies utilising Mob/Pair Programming
- Unit Testing with React Testing Library for code reliabilityEfficiently managed collaboration through GitHub branches
- Designed an intuitive and visually appealing UI/UX
- Robust API implementation using Express and Node.js

Sole Contributor (duration 1 week)

09/2023 - 09/2023

BrewDog Online Shop - React, MongoDB 7

- · Demonstrated strong problem-solving skills and adaptability while working independently
- · Successfully designed and developed a personal project from the ground up, demonstrating full-stack development skills
- Proficient use of CSS for a polished user interface, mimicking existing BrewDog website

Sole Contributor (duration 1 week)

08/2023 - 08/2023

SERVivors Tennis Club Booking System 7

- Gained initial experience in web development using Python, Flask, and PostgreSQL
- · Demonstrated commitment, as a beginner, to project planning and development
- · Debugging using Breakpoints and Trace Points

EXPERIENCE

Software Development Student

07/2023 - 11/2023

CodeClan - CodeBase

The CodeClan 16-week course was an incredible learning experience that lasted over 800 hours. It provided a deep and comprehensive education in software development. During the program, I had the opportunity to explore programming fundamentals, focusing on languages such as Python, Java and JavaScript while emphasising best practices.

Sales Manager 11/2017 - 05/2023

CCG Homes Ltd

- Sales Department Startup: Receiving Multiple Awards and Exceeding Sales Targets by 20% Over GDV
- · Marketing Management: Sales Materials, Market Analysis, ensuring accuracy at all times
- Product Development: Guiding and enhancing designs, specifications, and efficiency, along side Architects and Engineers
- · Team Support: Staff Reviews, appraisals, and meeting targets
- · Process Enhancement: Designing and implementing efficient procedures, improving flow of information and reporting
- · Problem-Solving: Design and specification challenges during build stages
- · Legal Expertise: Ensuring compliance at all times
- Engagement/Networking: Events and Building Key Relationships

Head of Sales 01/2007 - 11/2017

Dandara Ltd

- · Sales Department Launch: From Inception
- · Leadership Advancement: Sales Person, Manager, Head of Sales North East
- Diverse Development Management: Guiding projects for various buyer preferences. Ensuring all sites were staffed and sales areas well presented
- · Staff Management: Support, training, appraisals, recruitment
- · Innovative Process Enhancement: New and existing processes refined to maximise productivity and efficiency
- · Legal: Liaising with solicitors from pre-sales to completion

SKILLS

Front End PostgreSQL **JavaScript** MongoDB React Express.js HTML & CSS Node.js User Experience Design Spring Boot Python Hibernate Full Stack Java SOLID / OOP Principles Git

EDUCATION

Professional Software Development

07/2023 - 11/2023

CodeClan

SCQF Level 8

HNC Software Development

08/1994 - 06/1997

Reid Kerr College

SCQF 3, 4, 5, 6, 7

CERTIFICATES

Front-End Software Engineering virtual experience programme on Forage

12/2023 - Present

Skyscanner

- Completed a job simulation where I built a web application using React as a front-end engineer at Skyscanner.
- Developed a page for picking a travel date using Skyscanner's open-source Backpack React library.
- · Customised my application and ran automated tests to ensure it rendered properly.

Single Sales Principle 07/2022 - Present

100% Pass with Distinction

Management Training 7 03/2012 - Present

Pareto Law

HOBBIES

In my free time, I'm a pro at making life interesting! You'll often find me pedaling through scenic routes, which doubles as my excuse for an extra slice of cake.

I've also earned my stripes in the DIY realm - I'm the one you call when your bookshelf turns into a Rubik's Cube. And let's not forget tennis, where I've managed to master the art of hitting the ball into mysterious dimensions of the court (sometimes unintentionally).

When I'm not busy chasing tennis balls, I'm out in the great outdoors with my Dog, Carmen. I believe in "eargasmic" experiences, so I dabble in music, both as a listener and, occasionally, a shower-time rockstar.

Recently, I've explored some daring adventures in the world of short courses. From pottery (yes, I've managed to create some questionable art) to sewing

(let's just say my stitching skills have improved from "catastrophic" to "not-so-catastrophic"), and even golf (don't ask about my golf swing; it's a work in progress).

So, whether I'm pedaling, DIY-ing, serving aces, or creating pottery masterpieces (questionable as they may be), you can bet I'm making memorable moments at every turn!